Praise the mighty Rapu.
我全能的 Rapu 神呐.
I pray to you.
我向您祈求.
For water and sustenance.
水和食物.
I pray to you, not for me...
我向您祈祷，不为自己
But for my daughter.
只为我的女儿
I'm tired.
我太累了
Ah, what do we have here?
哈，这谁呀
Look at it...
看看它
Gobbling up all my fruit.
狼吞虎咽我的水果
Rapu.
Rapu 神啊
Bringer of light.
光之神
Oh, it's one of mine.
哈，还是我的人
I am Gorr.
我叫 Gorr
The last of your disciples.
您是您最后剩下的追随者了
We have lost everything, my lord.
我们失去了一切，我的主啊
The land is dry.
大地干旱
All life is lost.
一切生命都逝去了
We have faith in you, never wavered.
我们始终追随着您，从未动摇
And now we await the promise...
而现在我们终于盼来了您承诺的...
of the eternal reward.
永恒的奖赏。
Is this why you celebrate?
这就是您在此欢庆的原因吧
He thinks there's an eternal reward.
哈 它认为有永恒的奖赏。
No... No, sorry.
不... 不，抱歉了
There's no eternal reward for you, dog!
根本就没有永恒的奖赏给你，狗！
What we're celebrating is a fresh kill.
我们是在庆祝一次胜利击杀
We just vanquished the holder of the Necrosword.
我们刚刚放倒了死灵之剑的持有者
Before he could harm any other
gods with that cursed blade.
在他用那受诅咒之剑继续屠杀神明之前
- You see...
- Threaten to end my entire empire.
威胁要终结我的帝国
But my lord...
但我的主啊
Your empire has already ended.
您的帝国已经完结了
There's no one left to worship you.
已经没剩活着的人继续信奉您了
There'll be more followers to replace you.
放心 会有更多的追随者取代你们的
There always are.
一直是如此
We have suffered...
我们遭受苦难
And we have starved.
我们被活活饿死
My daughter died...
我女儿死了
in your name.
在你的庇护下
And well, you should.
那个，这就是你们应该遭遇的
Suffering for your gods
is your only purpose.
这就是你们活着的唯一目的
There's nothing for you after death...
而你们死后也啥都不会有
...except death!
除了死亡
You are no god.
你这算什么神
I renounce you.
我要放弃信奉你
Now, your meaningless life...
那么现在， 你毫无意义的生命
...finally does have a purpose.
... 终于要有点作用了
To sacrifice yourself to me.
就是把你的生命献祭给我
So it's revenge you seek...
那么你想要复仇是吧
Kill all the gods.
杀光所有神明
Go to Eternity.
前往永恒
It's revenge you seek.
那有你寻求的复仇
Hammer...
The Bifrost...
召唤彩虹桥...
Eternity...
前往永恒...
Hammer...
The Bifrost...
召唤彩虹桥...
Eternity.
前往永恒.
So the sword chose you...
死灵剑选择了你...
But you are now cursed.
但你也同样被诅咒了
Funny...
那奇怪了...
It doesn't feel like a curse.
我怎么不感觉这是个诅咒
Feels like a promise.
更像是个承诺
So this is my vow...
这将是我的誓言
All gods will die.
所有的神都得死
Come, gather round...
来，聚一聚
And listen to the legend
of the Space Viking.
听我给你们讲太空维京海盗的传奇
a.k.a. "The God of Thunder".
又名“雷神”
a.k.a. "Thor Odinson".
又名“索尔 奥丁之子”
Raised in the way of the Warrior...
以战士的方式养大
Thor was taught to
help bring balance.
索尔被教导要帮助带来平衡
Fighting the good fight, for
those who can't fight neither.
为那些无力抵抗的人 打好仗
He grew.
他成长啊
And he grew.
长啊
继续长
He was sensitive,
like a smile.
他好似一抹微笑般感性
And his loving nature
did not discriminate.
而且他爱的本性也从不歧视
He once loved a swashbuckling Pasanita.
他曾经爱过一个风度翩翩的帕萨尼塔
Another time, he
loved a wolf woman...
还有一次，他
爱上了一个狼女…
on a woman wolf.
骑在女狼上
But Thor's one true love was an
Earth woman named Jane Fonda.
但索尔的真爱是个地球女人，名叫简·方达
But, wait no...
不对
Jane Foster.
简·福斯特
But sadly...
但很遗憾...
In the battle for love, Thor lost.
在爱情之战中，索尔输了
In fact,
he lost a lot of people in those days.
事实上，在那些日子里，他也输掉了很多人
His mum.
他妈咪
His dad.
他爹地
And that guy.
和这个人
And that guy...
Whoever that is.
还有不管这是谁
And Heimdall.
还有海姆达尔
And his brother.
还有他弟弟
And his brother again.
还又一次他弟弟
And again.
还又来一次
Poor Thor had to watch
his planet explode.
可怜的索尔不得不看他的星球爆炸
And then he said,
"What have I done?"
然后他说，
“我做了什么？”
it seemed that everything
and everyone he loved, he lost.
似乎他所爱的一切，他都失去了
And so he hid his heart
behind a big, fleshy bod...
于是他把内心藏在了一个肥躯后面……
So it could never be broken again.
这样他就不会再伤心
But just because he was done loving,
didn't mean he was done fighting.
但虽然他不打算爱了，
并不意味着他不战了
He teamed up with
the Guardians of the Galaxy...
他与银河护卫队组队
and set off on some
classic Thor adventures.
并开始了一些崭新的雷神冒险
He got in shape...
他训练恢复身材...
Putting in the hard yards...
刻苦训练
Turning pains into gains...
化痛苦为收获
And never skipping leg day.
而且从不略过练腿日
He went from dad bod to god bod
他从老爹体态变成了神之身姿
But beneath this god bod...
但藏在这副神躯之下的
There was still still a sad bod,
just trying to get out.
仍然是那个悲伤的灵魂，想要冲破阴霾
Because all of the bods that
Thor had worn over the years...
因为多年来，不管索尔体型怎么变
Couldn't hide the pain
that he was feeling on the inside.
都无法掩饰他来自内心深处的痛苦
So, he gave up his search for nothing.
于是，他不再寻觅任何事情
Accepting that he was
only good for one thing.
接受了他一直以来的使命
Waiting in quiet contemplation
for someone to say...
在静静的冥想中等待有个人来跟他说
Thor...
雷神
We need your help
to win this battle.
我们需要你的帮助来拿下这场战争
Thor...
雷神
We need your help
to win this battle.
我们需要你的帮助来拿下这场战争
Let's go.
我们走吧
Alright, I'm game.
好吧
Come on, Stormbreaker.
来吧，风暴战锤
Woah, Thor!
You okay?
动作快点儿, 好吧
People are dying.
人们正战死杀场呢
See you down there.
下面见
Hurry up!
快点
Gimme those!
松嘴
You're gonna break it.
都要给你咬坏了
- I am Groot!
- Oh, you got sap all over it.
- 哎呀， 全是你的哈喇子
Hello, everybody!
大家好呀
Well, well...
Look who it is!
看看 这是谁呀！
- How are we doing, guys?
- Horrible!
- 你们怎么样了
- 糟透了
We're all going to die!
我们都要葬身于此了
You said, this planet
would be a relaxing holiday.
你还说来这个星球是个放松的度假
I said, it was going to
be like a relaxing holiday.
我是说会像是个放松的度假
Well, look at our resplended
skystone prefound spat.
看看那壮观的天际
What can be more
relaxing than that?
还有什么能比这更放松心情的
An actual holiday!
一个真正的假期
Die, mutant scum!
去死吧，变异人渣
- God of Thunder!
- King Yakan.
- 雷神
- 亚坎国王
You have finally joined our fight.
你终于来加入我们的战斗了
Well, as they say,
better late than not at all.
就像人们说的，迟到总比不来强
It's very nice.
你可真好
As you know, we
used to live in peace.
您知道，我们一直过着和平的生活
- But then, our gods were murdered.
- Murdered?
- 但是突然 我们信奉的所有神明都被谋杀了
- 谋杀了？
And now, our sacred temple
has been left unguarded...
现在我们的神殿 无人掌管
And Habooska's horde
took control of it.
就被哈布斯卡的部落占领了
...Sacred shrine is desecrated.
我们这最神圣的神社就这样被亵渎了
Not for long.
不会持续多久了
King Yakan...
亚坎王
Tell them what happened here today.
要将今天在这里发生的事流传下去
Know the time that Thor...
是雷神
Ragtag, motley crew,
misfit desperados...
和这些不合群的亡命之徒
Found the time to battle and
etch their names in history.
抽时间为这场具有历史意义战斗正名
The odds may be against us...
也许暂时我们处于下风
- Bu t I'll tell you this for free.
- Here we go.
- 但是我要免费告诉你
- 又来了
This ends here, and now!
现在就此结束
Please don't let him
go into the temple.
别告诉我他要冲入神庙了
Well done, everybody.
干得不错，大家
We can collectively take credit for that,
since we worked as a team.
你们也可以跟着一起邀功, 既然我们都是一个团队了
We used our hearts and
our minds to defeat the enemy...
我们用毅力战胜了敌人
With minimal loss or damages.
将损失降至了最低
What a classic Thor adventure.
多么经典的雷神冒险呀
Hurrah!
欧耶!
Good book?
好看吗
Yeah.
不错
I wrote it.
我写的
You're...
You're Dr. Jane Foster?
你是 ..
你是简·福斯特博士？
I am.
是我
- Hi!
How's the Einstein-Rosen bridge?
爱因斯坦-罗森桥怎么样？
Tough.
挺难的
- Yeah.
- Really tough.
- 是吗
- 真难懂
You need a 3D model.
你需要个3D模型
You ever seen Event Horizon?
你看过“事件视界”吗
No.
没
- Interstellar?
- No.
- “星际穿越”呢？
- 没
That movie explains
everything really clearly.
那部电影解释的还挺清晰的
Um, alright.
额，好吧
The Einstein-Rosen
bridge folds space...
爱因斯坦-罗森桥可以折叠空间
So that unique A and unique B
will coexist in space, like that.
让点A和点B 有时候可以在太空中共存，就像这样
You just ruined your own book.
你弄坏了你自己的书
Yeah, but now you understand wormholes.
是，但是现在你了解虫洞了
- You watch those movies.
- Okay.
- 去看那些电影
- 好的
Ah, the hot Cheetos.
Had to get it.
哈，辣味奇多
必选这个
So how's the...
How's the club?
那么 化疗俱乐部感觉如何?
It's going amazing.
棒极了
Have you...
你有没有
Told anyone else besides me?
告诉其他人这事儿 除了我
When people find out.
they start acting weird.
当人们知道了，就会变现得很别扭
They're just...
他们只是
different.
不能感同身受
And I'm not afraid now.
而且我现在已经不害怕了
Anyway, it's not contagious.
无论如何，这又不会传染
Jane, it's stage four.
简，这已经是第四阶段了
Out of like, how many stages?
没事儿，我是说总共有那么多阶段呢
- Four.
- That we know about.
- 就四个
- 据我们所知的
Oh, you have uh...
哦，你还有
Somewhere else you gotta be right now,
that's more important than chemo.
什么事要去做吗，比化疗还重要的
No...
没有...
You're trying to get back
to the lab, aren't you?
你是想回实验室吧？
- I have a few ideas I'm trying.
- Okay, no. Time out.
- 我有些新的想法想要验证下
- 别闹了
I know you think your lab work
is something you have to do.
我知道你认为实验工作你不做不行
Otherwise, you're letting
down all civilization, but...
要不然就要让人类文明失望了
You're not getting what the universe
is actually trying to tell you...
你还没接收到宇宙一直在想要传达给你的信息吗
So let me translate.
好吧，我来翻译一下
Slow.
Down.
慢慢来
Use your energy to fight this thing.
保留点儿体力对抗这病魔吧
I'll fight it my way, okay?
我会用我的方式对抗
Um, FYI...
额，顺便说句
"My way" does not have
to equal alone in a lab.
“我的方式”不需要非得是孤独的呆在实验室里
Maybe it's time to play
the Space Viking card.
也许是使出太空维京卡的时候了
- It's not a card.
- Yes, it is.
- 他不是张卡
- 是的 他是
- There's no card.
- There's a card.
- 根本就没有卡
- 是有的
It's tall, and blonde,
and it's gorgeous.
是张又高、又有趣又惊艳的卡
It is a handsome card.
确实是张帅气的卡
Jane, are you sure?
简，你决定了吗
I will figure this out...
我会想办法的
By myself.
靠我自己
Results are just
coming back the same.
结果出来了 可惜还是一样
I'm afraid the chemo
has very little effect.
恐怕化疗的效果微乎其微
I'm so sorry, Jane.
真的非常抱歉，简
If there's anything I can do
or if you just wanna talk, call me.
如果有什么我能做的
或你只想找人说说话，打给我
Smell like a king...
闻起来就像个国王
Because you're worth it.
因为您值得拥有
Old Spice.
老料牌
Look at this place.
It's beautiful, oh.
看这地方呐，真美啊
You're home, Father.
父亲
- We're here to take you home.
- Yes.
- 我们这就带您回家
- 是呀
To Planet Asgard.
回阿斯加德星球
Asgard is not a planet, my sons.
阿斯加德不是个星球，我的孩子
It is a people.
It is you.
是上面生活着的人民，是你们
And now it is time for me
to pass on to the spirit realm.
而现在的我该是时候踏上神域了
I will take my place
我会在那找到我的位置
in the great banqueting hall of Valhalla,
the resting place of the gods.
瓦尔哈拉的宴会厅中，众神的安息之地
Oh, one more thing.
哦，还有件事
You have a sister.
你们有个姐姐
And so now I turn into godly
stardust and say farewell.
现在，我要化成金色星尘和你们道别了
Oh, look.
哦 看呐
Do you see?
看到了吗
Dad?
父亲
I've disappeared.
我正在消逝
- No!
- Father!
- 不！
- 父亲！
But wait, brother!
等等，兄弟
An ominous portal has appeared behind us.
一个不详的传送门出现在了我们身后
Transform!
变身！
I am Hela,
Goddess of Death.
我是海拉，死亡女神
Now, I return to Asgard, to stake my
claim as the rightful heir to the throne.
现在我要回到阿斯加德，继承我应有的王位
And no one will stop me!
没人能再阻止我了！
Join me or die.
俯首称臣吧 要么就去死
- We'll never join you, witch.
- Mjölnir.
- 我们是永远不会加入你的，女巫
Impossible!
不可能！
I broke your hammer!
我捏碎了你的锤子
Time to die!
受死吧
- Bifrost!
- 彩虹桥
You can almost feel the power
你几乎可以感觉到
of these magnificent and immovable stones.
蕴藏在这些奇幻的无法移动的碎片中的力量
Okay, let's head back to the village...
好了，让我们回到村庄
where we can drink
some real Asgardian mead.
去品尝下纯正的阿斯加德蜂蜜酒
Come on.
来吧
God of Disaster...
破坏之神
We thank you.
我们感谢您
We feared we would be at war forever
without the protection of our gods.
我们还担心没了神明的庇护，我们会从此陷入无限的争战
But now, peace shall reign.
但现在，和平将至
In return for your service,
please accept these gifts.
作为对您的报答，请收下这些礼物
It is tradition, protectors of our
world are bestowed a great, big...
这是个传统，我们世界的捍卫者将被赐予一个伟大的...
- Giant goat?
- Oh, look at those. They are wonderful.
- 巨大山羊
- 哇, 看呐，太绝了
Korg, look at that.
Those are little wonderfuls.
Korg, 看呐
太美了
King Yakan,
thank you so much.
雅康王，太感谢了
Listen um...
about the temple.
听着 至于寺庙嘛
- I don't want to talk about the temple.
- I know, but if we were to talk about it.
- 我不想谈论圣庙。
- 我知道， 但如果我们恰好谈到的话
- It's important... Fine, I'll stop.
- It's making me sad and mad.
- 这是很重要的 .. 好吧， 我不提了
- 那让我又伤心...又生气
Don't forget the goats.
别忘了你的山羊
We should have kept them sacred.
既然你都接受了，你可必须得带走它们
No whacking.
不要乱撞
Awh, they are beautiful.
它们真的是美极了
Yes, they are beautiful.
是呀，它们是挺美的
- They also scream quite a lot.
- That'll be fine.
- 它们也挺能叫唤的
- 没事儿
We need to find a damn. Mostly, so
we can download the distress signal.
我们要找到那该死的遥控器，这样我们就能下载到呼救信号了
I'll retrace your steps.
Where did you put the remote?
你都去过哪里，可能把遥控器放哪了
One of the goats
probably ate it.
可能被其中的一只山羊吃了也说不定
Don't get ignorant.
Don't be ridiculous.
山羊不会吃的
可别开玩笑了
Alright, he can do that crap.
好吧，它确实有可能做出这破事儿
I love them.
我爱它们
We need more pavers,
on the double.
- 它们要跟我们一直到永远
- 找到遥控器了
I'm putting him down.
我要把它放倒
Me too!
别开枪
No, it's not working.
It's not charged.
- 不 不能用了
- 没充电
Well maybe, you need
to find the centrifuge.
那也许你得找到充电器
- Korg, you okay?
- Yeah, bro. All good.
- Korg, 你还好把
- 是的，没事儿
Alright.
Everybody, just relax.
好吧，听着大家，先放轻松
The goats are going
to be fine.
山羊不会有啥大问题的
If not, turn them to meat.
如果有问题，再做成肉
King people.
Meat-eating people.
再带他们去见国王一行人 (meat肉和 meet见 同音)
- They have great conversation starters.
- And you told me to come in the middle.
- 它们也是很好的破冰话题
- 而且他们告诉我用这种特殊的口哨就可以召唤它们
- Ichu Musu.
- Yeah, something like that.
有点像是这样
No, that's not it.
不是这个
也不是这个
你试试
Not it, but you had a good one.
不，也不是
- Hey, guys!
- Kraglin!
- 嘿, 大伙们
You've been here,
this whole time?
你哪冒出来的，你一直在这吗
Yeah, you said to
stay with the ship.
是呀，你不是说要一直呆在船上吗
This is Glenda.
We're married.
这是格兰达，我们结婚了
I am Groot.
What did I tell you about
jumping into new relationships?
我是怎么跟你说关于步入新恋情的
- That I shouldn't be that.
- Yeah!
- 说我不应该这么做
- 对呀
You can't get married on
every single planet we land on.
你也不能每到个新星球都结个婚呐
I am Groot.
Finally!
终于好使了
Alright, here we go.
"Distress Calls".
好了，来了， “求救频道”
Please help us!
The God Butcher, you have to help us!
求你们救救我们, 屠神者来了，快来救救我们
God Butcher?
屠神者？
- It's just a dragon.
- It's a warning!
All of these gods murdered.
看这些被屠杀的神明呀
Our greatest champions...
我们最强大的冠军
Now laid to waste.
现在被撂倒了
The horror.
如噩梦般
Who could have done something like this?
是谁能做出这种事情呀
- Where are you?
- Wait, wait, wait.
- 你在哪
- 等等
What was that?
Go, go, go back.
那是什么，回去，退回去
Play that one.
播放这个
Thor, where are you?
雷神，你在哪
- Sif.
- We need you here.
- 西芙
- 我们需要你
Well, my friend is in danger.
We must go at once.
我朋友命在旦夕，我们得立刻出发
Start the ship, my friend.
启动飞船，我的朋友
Oh. Maybe,
we should split up.
额，也许，我们得分头行动
So many people to save, I mean.
我意思是，有太多得人等待救援了
Look at all these distress... calls.
看所有这些呼救呀
Thor, you're gonna be okay?
索尔，你会没事儿的吧？
I admire your commitment to each other.
It's a beautiful thing.
我钦佩你们对彼此的忠诚，是多么的美好且珍贵
Alas, it's something
I'll never have.
虽然，那是我永远都不会再拥有的
Buddy, if I may
兄弟，我有些话不知当讲不当讲
You may.
请说
After thousands of years of living, you
don't seem to know who the hell you are.
活了几千年，你似乎还是没弄清楚你到底是谁
I've been lost before.
我之前也迷失过
Then I found meaning,
I found love.
但我还是找到了生命的意义，我找到了真爱
And yeah, I got taken
from being a god, that hurts.
是的, 她也被夺走了, 天呐，那真是伤心
But that shitty feeling is
better than feeling empty.
但是，这糟糕的感觉也比什么感觉都没有要强
My hope for you is that one day,
you will find something...
我希望有朝一日，你也能找到任何
To make you feel this shitty.
能让你为之所动的糟糕感觉
I have loved.
我也爱过
Didn't work out.
没能走下去
They either die a brutal death or
they dump you with the handwritten letter.
要么他们死的惨烈，要么用封手写信把你给甩了
I don't know which is worse, which is
why I keep everyone at arm's length.
我不知道哪个更糟糕，也是为什么我一直与人保持着一臂之距
I've grown too attached, damn it!
I knew this would happen.
该死的，我已经开始越来越依恋你们了！
我就知道这会发生
You must go!
你们必须走！
I'll find, Sif.
我会去找西芙
You answer the other calls.
你们去回应其他求助
The Galaxy needs its guardians.
银河需要它的守护者们
- Cool, yeah. We were just thinking.
- Listen, I know this hurts.
- 太好了，我们刚刚还想说..
- 听着，我知道这对你们来说很难接受
But it's better this way.
You have to trust me.
但只能这样了，你必须相信我
To ease the pain,
why don't you uh...
为了减轻些痛苦，你们为什么不
Take the ship here,
as a parting farewell gift.
开走这艘飞船，作为我们分别的礼物
Oh, you're giving me my ship?
额，你是在送我的船给我吗？
Yes, she's yours.
是的，她是你的了
Let you make as many
memories with her as I have.
就让你们也跟我一样与她共同经历出更多美好的回忆吧
She's a temperamental old lass.
她是个脾气暴躁的老姑娘
Serve you well,
in a tight pickle.
但她会照顾好你们的
- Start the ship?
- Thank you.
- 启动飞船
- 谢谢
Goodbye, old friend.
再见了，老朋友
Human handshake.
人类握手
Guardian shake.
阿斯加德握手
Into the snake that
you cannot trust.
变成你不能信任的毒蛇
- Really, dragon is uh...
- Finish the classic of Guardian high one.
- 认真得吗，别再拖延了
- 最后是经典的阿斯加德高一
- Let's go.
- Take care of my crew.
- 快出发吧
- 照顾好我的船员
It's going to be
hard for them.
这对他们来说将会挺难接受的
- Hurry up!
- Not her.
- 别磨蹭了！
- 除了她
Remember what I told you.
记住我跟你说的
You ever feel loss?
再感到迷失
Just look into the eyes
of the people that you love.
就望向你爱着的人们的双眸
They'll tell you exactly who you are.
他们会确切的告诉你 你到底是谁
Alright, bye.
好了，拜
Once more, but we
had good memories.
又一次我们创造了美好的回忆
We Asgardians say, "May you travel
with the speed of Odin's ravens".
阿斯加德人会说，"愿你们以奥丁的信鸦般的速度旅行"
I'll see you in Valhalla
where we will drink mead.
我会在瓦尔哈拉与你们团聚
我们会在那里喝蜂蜜酒
They're gone.
他们已经走了
Alone again, me and you.
又剩你和我了
Stormbreaker!
风暴战斧！
Be careful with your crazy ax.
小心点你这疯狂的斧头
So what are we
gonna do, brother?
我们现在要干什么，兄弟？
Let's go get Sif.
我们去救西芙
Who or what is that?
他是什么或是谁
Falligar,
God of the Phaligarians.
法利加，法利加人的神
One of the nicest
gods you'll ever meet.
会是你能遇到过最好的神了
Sif!
It's me, Thor.
西芙！
是我，索尔
Odin's son.
奥丁之子
You're missing an arm.
你少了条胳膊
Let me get you home.
我这就送你回家
No!
不！
Leave me here.
留我在这
I want to die a warrior's death.
我将以战士般去赴死
On the battlefield, in battle.
在战场上，在战斗中
And then I can claim my place in Valhalla.
然后就能在瓦尔哈拉占据我的一席之地了
Oh, I hate to break it to you.
哦，非常抱歉我不得不跟你解释下
But for a warrior
to get into Valhalla,
战士如果想去瓦尔哈拉
you have to die in the battle.
你必须得战死沙场
- You survived.
- Ah, shit!
- 而你已经活下来了
- 啊，该死！
Maybe, your arm is in Valhalla.
也许你的手臂已经到瓦尔哈拉了
What happened to this?
这是怎么回事？
I've been hunting a lot of men.
我一直在追捕一个疯子
I followed him here!
我随他踪迹跟到这里
- It was a trap.
- Who is this mad man?
- 结果却落入陷阱
- 这疯子是谁？
The God Butcher,
he's coming.
屠神者，他快来了
He seeks the extinction of the gods.
他誓要灭绝神明
Asgard is next.
阿斯加德是下一个
- Look, it's Thor! Thor!
- Take Sif to the infirmary.
- 看呐，是雷神，雷神
- 快带西芙去医务室
Hey! Who'd you piss off now?
嘿， 这回你又把谁惹毛了？
It's not my fault.
不管我的事儿
I've never even seen these things,
whoever the hell they are.
我从没见过这些，不管这是啥东西
Welcome back.
欢迎回来
Die!
去死吧！
Whos' the new guy?
新人是谁呀？
That guy...
You're gonna love that guy.
那家伙... 你会爱上那家伙的
Mjölnir.
Mjölnir!
It's me, Thor.
是我啊，索尔
Have you seen my hammer?
你们看到我锤子了吗
Mjölnir, here boy.
Mjölnir?
Mjölnir.
You're back.
你回来了
Mjölnir!
'Scuse me.
Hello.
不好意思
That's my hammer, you bonehead.
那可是我的锤子，你个憨憨
and that's my look.
这还是我的造型
Hey!
Enough tomfoolery, wench.
别闹了 丫头
Take off that mask
and reveal yourself.
摘掉那面具现出你自己
Granted.
明了
Hey.
Jane?!
简?
Let me tell you the
legend of Thor and Jane.
让我来给你们讲个索尔与简的传奇故事
He was a God of Thunder.
他曾是雷神
And she, a woman of science.
而她，是个女科学家
And although they were
from different worlds...
虽然他们来自不同世界
Somehow, it just made sense.
然而不知为何，他们还是水到渠成
And together, they embarked
on the journey of love.
两人一起，踏上了爱情的旅程
Thor taught Jane,
the way of the warrior.
索尔教给简无畏的战士之道
And Jane taught Thor,
the way of the people.
而简教给索尔人际之道
And as time passed, their
love grew deeper and deeper.
渐渐的，他们对彼此的爱越来越深
Incredible.
Isn't she, Mjölnir?
她真是太难以置信了，不是吗，Mjonir
I need you to promise me,
you'll always protect her.
我需要你向我保证，你会一直守护着她
I love you too, buddy.
我也爱你，老铁
A love that deep, has a way
of becoming magical.
爱之深切，都产生了魔法效应
Thor set a path towards a future
and all it might hold.
索尔为未来开辟了道路，也明白一切可能的走向
But the more he pondered a life with Jane,
the more he feared losing that life.
当他越是畅想着与简的生活，他越是害怕有天终会失去
And although Jane didn't want to admit it,
而虽然简也不想承认
she was scared of loss as well.
但她也非常害怕一切终会从指尖流逝
And so, they built walls between them.
于是，两人都渐渐的筑起了高墙
Thor got busy,
saving humanity.
索尔一天天忙着拯救人类
Heimdall!
海姆达尔
Jane got busy, doing the same.
简 同样的也忙于科研
Real busy.
特别忙
And eventually, the space
between them grew and grew
慢慢的 两人间的距离愈来愈远
Until it became too wide to bear.
直到这距离远得难以承受
Some things
had to give.
总要有人做出妥协
I have to stay up all night,
then go through this data.
我得熬夜整理这么多得数据
While I just stay up all night
eating and clean all of this up.
而我为等你也熬了一夜，又自己吃又得收拾这一桌子
There's two plates!
就俩盘子
And then one night,
it didn't give.
终于有一晚，没有妥协只剩下了失去
Jane wrote a note.
简留了张字条
And Thor read that note.
索尔读这张字条
And their legend
suddenly became myth.
而这传奇的一对儿 就这样戛然而止
Or so they thought.
或是他们是这么认为的
You okay?
你还好吗
Yes.
是
It's a little hot,
isn't it?
只是有点喘不过气
It's just a feeling.
可能只是对这头盔
Bit claustrophobic
with the helmet.
有点幽闭恐惧
How?!
怎么回事?!
Can we talk about this later?
我能过后再给你解释吗?
Yeah, sure.
当然
Great seeing you!
很高兴见到你!
What?!
什么情况?!
Hey! Is that the Necrosword?
嘿! 这是死灵之剑吗?
That's cool. I've only ever
read about it in stories.
酷, 我还只是在书中读到过它
Then, you know
this is going to hurt.
那你应该知道这剑的厉害了
Pain.
疼痛
What is pain, but a construct
invented by the weak.
啥是疼痛,  那只不过是弱者发明的一个概念
Oh, okay!
That's very sharp!
啊, 别!
这个是有点锋利!
Ready?
Hey
准备好了吗?
Don't touch my things.
别瞎碰我的东西
You better run,
you coward.
你最好逃跑, 你个怂货
The children!
They're taking the children!
孩子! 他带走了孩子们!
- Mommy!
- 妈妈
- Dad!
- Mom!
- 爸爸
- 妈妈
Mother!
妈妈!
Shadow monsters,
disgusting.
暗影怪物, 真是卑鄙
Flew around the world twice, nothing.
绕地球飞两圈了, 没发现任何踪迹
Cowards must have run away.
We'll find them.
这孬种肯定逃走了, 会给我们找到的
- Quite a reunion, huh?
- Ah, you're telling me.
- 真是个突然的重逢呐
- 可不是嘛
What's it been like?
Three, four years?
这都过了多久了?
得有三, 四年了吧
Eight years, seven months and six days.
八年, 七个月 零 六天
I haven't forgotten.
我没忘呢
The last time I saw you or
didn't see you, because you left.
上次我见到你或是没见到你, 因为你离开了
Kind of an oversimplification
to say that I left.
说是我离开了有点过于简化了吧
Ah, no, you left.
You did.
确实是你离开了呀
You wrote me
a beautiful handwritten letter.
你给我留了封漂亮的手写信
I should know,
I was there.
我知道, 因为当时我就在那
- You weren't there, actually.
- I was.
- 事实上是你不在,
- 我在
And the note...
才有的信
And if you weren't there to see me
leave, then maybe it was you that left.
如果你没眼见我离开，那也许是你离开了
Fair point.
是有点道理
- Not that matters, like...
- No.
- 反正现在也都不重要了 不是吗
- 是啊
- Keeping track, right?
- Yeah.
- 继续搜索吧
- 对
It's supposed we both left
and both got left.
应该是我们都离开了, 也都被离开了
Now, you're leaving again.
而现在, 你又正在离开我
Miek, we need detailed
accounts from all the witnesses.
米克, 我们需要所有目击者的详细陈述。
Darryl, get all the names of the
children who've been lost.
达里尔, 列出所有失踪孩子的姓名
- Your Majesty, my daughter isn't here.
- Don't worry.
- 陛下, 我的女儿被带走了
- 别担心
And she'll be found.
她会被找到的
Guys, they're bleeding!
Get them to the infirmary, now!
伙计, 他们正流血呢, 赶紧送去医务室
- Darryl!
- Madison.
Should we start working on a
performance of this entire debacle?
我们是不是应该对这场灾难做次表演?
People need entertainment.
人们需要放松娱乐
Particularly now,
in times of crisis.
尤其是在这危急的时刻
Who did this?
尤其的
I did not hear a "no".
我没听到她回应"不"
Nor did I.
我也没听到
Asgard, at night.
阿斯加德, 夜晚
We open on some
sleeping children.
我们将几个睡梦中的孩子作为开幕
So that's the ex-girlfriend, is it?
这就是传说中的前女友是吧?
- The old ex-girlfriend,
- Jane Foster.
- 又是老套的前女友情节
- 简 福斯特
- Jane Foster.
- The one that got away.
- 简 福斯特
- 一个爱情的逃兵
The one that got away.
一个爱情的逃兵
- That means escaped.
- Yeah.
- 就是说她成功逃脱了
- 是啊
Yeah.
是啊
Must be hard for you
to see your ex-girlfriend
一定很难吧对你来说
看到你的前任女友
and your ex-hammer
hanging out in here.
和你的前任战锤在一起了现在
What you up to, bro?
你干啥呢 兄弟?
Come on.
来吧
Come to daddy.
来爹地这
Come on, Mjölnir.
来呀, Mjonir
Hey, there you are!
嘿, 你在这儿呀
Hey!
嘿
- I was just calling you.
- ...Start an army.
- 我正召唤你呢
- 起兵
With what?
用什么起
- Half our soldiers are dead.
- Half our soldiers are always dead.
- 我们一半儿的士兵都挂了
- 我们一半儿的士兵早就挂了
- Everyone, please. Go home.
- Where are the children?
- 各位们, 请回家等消息
- 孩子们在哪?
And now, I promise
you will have news.
暂时先回家, 我保证会带来捷报
- I don't know.
- Can't go far.
- 我不知道
- 应该不会多远
I think the worst has happened.
我认为最糟糕的事情已经发生了
She'll find them.
女王会找到他们的
You know what?
这真是大错特错了
Asgard!
阿斯加德人们!
My friends,
we must not quarrel.
我的朋友们, 我们一定不要争吵
Times like this, we need
to unite and come together.
正是这种时刻, 我们才更应该团结
See what's happening here.
看到我们现在的情形了吗
We're afraid.
我们害怕了
Hm?
Scared.
恐惧了
Afraid.
害怕了
Anxious.
焦虑了
If we are to find the children,
we must first look within ourselves
如果要找到孩子们, 我们需要先审视我们的内心
I'm sorry, Miek.
打扰下 米克
It's very hard to give a rousing
speech with the eh-eh-eh noise.
想要给场振奋人心的讲话 真的是太难了, 在你这 嘤嘤嘤 的噪音下
What are you doing?
你干啥呢
- She's taking minutes.
- Well, precious minutes. We don't have.
- 她正花几分钟记录呢
- 这珍贵的几分钟 我们已经不再奢有了
Want the kids back?
想找回孩子们吗
I'll be back in a moment.
我去去就回
Write that down, Miek.
把这记录下来, 米克
Stormbreaker,
what are you doing?
风暴, 你搞什么飞机呢
Is this about Mjölnir?
这不会是跟旧锤有关吧
Everyone out!
都给我出去!
Didn't find 'em.
没找到
Your cape is on fire.
你披风着火了
It's fine,
it'll grow back.
没事儿, 它自己会长出来的
I'm invoicing you for this.
这窟窿我要跟你开发票了
Okay.
好
What do we know about this guy?
我们现在对这家伙了解多少?
He travels through shadows.
他能穿梭于暗影
And he creates
monsters with them.
而且他能创造出暗影怪物
Absolutely, spooky monsters.
还是极其诡异的怪物
Also wields the Necrosword.
他还手持死灵之剑
How do I know that?
问我怎么知道的
Because he almost speared
me in the face with it.
因为他差点就用它把我脸刺穿了
What's a Necrosword?
什么是死灵之剑
It's an ancient weapon that's been passed
through hands, since the dawn of time.
相传是自时间存在就传承下来的古代兵器
It has the ability to slay gods.
有能力屠戮众神
It slowly corrupts and kills
whoever wields it, which means...
它会慢慢侵蚀并腐化持有者, 也就意味着
- Oh, so it infected him.
- It's infecting him. Yes, it must be.
- 哦 剑正在影响着他的行为
- 是的, 他肯定是受剑影响的
So basically, we're up against a
cursed shadow, zombie kidnapper.
也就是说, 我们要面对一个影子僵尸绑匪
Awesome!
When do we leave?
好极了, 我们什么时候出发
Thor?
索尔?
- Can you see me?
- Uh, floating kid on the left.
- 能看到我吗
- 额, 左方漂出个头
Astrid
Heimdallson.
海姆达尔之子
Astrid, are you okay?
Astrid, 你们还好吧
I no longer go by the name, Astrid.
我不再用 Astrid 这名字了
I'm now known as Axl.
现在我的名字叫Axl
He's a singer from a
popular band I heard on Earth.
来自地球上一个流行乐队的主唱
GNR.
Astrid...
Your father gave you a very tough Viking
name and I intend to honor his wishes.
你父亲给了你个非常爷们儿的维京人名字, 我打算尊重他的意愿
- Axl.
- Astrid.
- I said, Axl.
- 我说了 Axl
- Astrid
- Axl!
- He's Axl! Now, listen to him.
- 他现在叫 Axl 了, 快听他的吧
Alright, fine.
"Axl"...
好吧, 好吧 Axl
- Where are you?
- I'm not sure.
- 你在哪?
- 我不确定
I don't know how to
use my magic powers yet.
我还不太会控制我的魔法
Your father told me
and I'm here to teach you.
你父亲曾教过我, 现在我来教你
I need you to focus
and hold out your hand.
我需要你集中注意力
伸出你的手
Okay, good.
很好
Now, focus.
Close your eyes.
集中, 闭上眼睛
Thor!
雷神
Hey!
How's it going, kids?
嘿, 孩子们, 你们还好吗
How's it going?
Look where we are.
看看我们现在的处境, 能好到哪去
We're in a cage made of spikes.
我们在一个尖刺笼子里
Yeah, that's right.
Not good.
是  对 不乐观
- You gonna do something?
- Yes. Yes, I am.
- 你能做点什么吗
- 是的我正在做
Just not right now.
I'm the vision ghost, look.
现在不行, 我现在是幻视灵魂, 看
- See.
- What will happen to us?
- 看到了?
- 他要对我们做什么
You can tell,
this is a very, very bad situation.
你们也能猜到, 我们正处于一个非常非常糟糕的境地
You know, the good news
is, you're Asgardian.
不过  好消息是 你们都是阿斯加德的后裔
So if you die, you'll end up in Valhalla.
所以如果你们死了, 将都会去往 瓦尔哈拉
Oh, my God, go away.
我去, 你还是走开吧
Okay, kids.
好了, 孩子们
Alright, kids. Don't cry.
You'll survive, okay?
好了, 孩子们, 别哭了, 没事儿了
Listen, I got a plan, okay?
听着, 我有一个计划 好吧
I'm putting together a
really, really good team.
我正在组建一支非常非常棒的营救小队
We've got
um, uh...
我们有, 额
Uncle Korg.
Korg叔叔
King Valkyrie.
国王 女武神
Um, yeah...
额, 对了
My ex-girlfriend, Jane, which is a whole
'nother story I won't bore you with, okay?
还有我的前任女友, 简, 那是另一个故事了, 我就不跟你们细说烦你们了, 好吧
But it is a top notch team, and we're
gonna have you home before you know it.
但这是个顶尖的队伍, 我们很快就来救你们回家了
Yeah.
I know where you are.
我知道你们在哪了
I'm gonna get
you out of here.
我会将你们救出来的
I'm scared.
我害怕
We all are.
我们都害怕
Look out for them.
Take care. Okay, take care.
照顾好大家, 保重, 好吧, 保重
See you soon, alright?
I'm gonna get you out of here.
一会儿见, 好吧
axl 赶紧把我从这弄出去
They're in the Shadow Realm.
他们身处影界
How do you know?
你怎么知道
The atmosphere there has
a darkness like no other.
那地方有一种独一无二的暗影氛围
As if color refused to tread.
It's unmistakable.
就像所有的色彩都被拒绝进入, 不可能搞错的
Well then,
if it's color we need.
这样的话, 如果我们需要色彩
Let's bring the rainbow.
让我们带上彩虹吧
Bring the rainbow? Is that a
catchphrase or something?
带上彩虹? 这是个新标语吗还是什么
She's only been a
Thor for a minute.
她才当上雷神一分钟
I mean, saving lives, she's quite good at.
But the rest is iffy.
我意思是, 拯救性命, 她很擅长, 但是其余的确实差点火候
- How many catchphrases have there been?
- A lot.
- 到现在她用过多少新口号了
- 很多
Yep, jumped the gun.
好吧，是有些仓促了
Hang on, he moves through shadows
and he's going to the shadow realm.
等下, 他可以自由出入于暗影, 而且他又身处影界
It seems like that's where he's
going to be the most powerful.
看来那应该是他最强大的地方
You're right. We can't
just go launching in there.
你说得对, 我们不能这么冒然过去
Could be a trap.
Could be endangering the children.
可能是个陷阱, 可能威胁到孩子们的安全
We need reinforcements.
We should raise an army.
我们需要增援, 我们需要组建一支军队
You thinking what I
think you're thinking?
你正在想我认为你正在想的地方吗
- I'm thinking it.
- What are we thinking?
- 我正在想
- 我们在想什么
- If you want, look into...
- Omnipotent City.
- 想什么
- 全能宫殿
What's Omnipotent City?
什么是全能宫殿
It's the home of the most
powerful gods of the universe.
那是全宇宙最强大的神明们的居住之地
We can put together the greatest team ever.
我们能组建一支有史来最伟大的队伍
We can recruit Ra,
Hercules, Tūmatauenga...
我们可能会招募到 拉(太阳神)，赫丘利斯(大力神)，图马陶恩加
Quetzalcóatl, maybe.
也许还有 克察尔科亚特尔
And Zeus, the oldest
and wisest of them all.
还有宙斯, 最古老也最贤明的神
- Did you say, Zeus?
- Yes, Zeus.
- 你刚刚是说了宙斯吗
- 是的 宙斯
Like the Zeus.
Zeus Zeus.
就是那个宙斯吗
宙斯的宙斯
I'm not sure if
he has a second name.
我不确定他还有复名
My god will be there,
Ninny of the Nonny.
我族的神也会在那, 妮妮闹妮神
...But if they are,
we'll ask them to join our team.
如果他在那, 我们能也招募他吗
Yes!
可以呀
Stormbreaker.
风暴战斧
Calm down, relax.
冷静点
No, no, no, mate.
不 不 不 伙计
We are not traveling on
Stormbreaker's janky Bifrost.
我们才不要在爆脾气的斧头召唤的彩虹桥上传送
Look what just happened.
你也看到刚才发生的了
We can't exactly go in your tiny
little flying portal horse, can we?
那我们也不能都驾你的传送小飞马去呀
- We won't all fit.
- What are you talking about?
- 也也驼不下我们全部人呐
- 你说什么呢
Warsong's awesome.
战歌 可厉害了
Stormbreaker's
awesome too.
风暴也厉害呀
Stormbreaker just
needs a conduit.
风暴战斧只是需要一个媒介
Anything that can
handle space travel.
任何能处理得来太空旅行的载体
I love it when she talks proper.
我喜欢她说专业术语的样子
It has the power
to get us there.
他拥有带我们穿行的能量
Just need something
to focus that energy
只是需要一个帮助他集中的舵手
So it's not so...
unpredictable.
让它得以掌控
You know, uh.
知道吧, 额
If we had a ship, we could harness it
and use Stormbreaker as a power source.
如果我们有艘船, 就可以利用风暴的能量作为动力
Ooh, like an engine.
哦, 就像是引擎
- Like an engine.
- You need a ship?
- 对 像是个引擎
- 你们需要船吗?
I got a ship.
正好我有船
Throw all those seats.
把座位都拆下来
There you go.
No, tie those goats to the front.
把俩羊牵在船头
We leave in 15 minutes.
15分钟后出发
Essentials only,
everyone.
只有必须品能上船 各位
That's essential.
这个很必须(酒桶)
Bet you moved on quick, didn't you.
看来你这么快就把我忘了, 是吧
You are some piece of work.
你还真是个狠角色
- Oh, hey!
- Hey.
- 哦 嘿
- 嘿
- Catching up with an old friend.
- Yeah.
- 只是在跟老朋友叙旧
- 是嘛
I've been meaning to apologize.
我在试图找机会道歉
Sort of acting a little weird before.
为我之前我奇怪的行为
I just haven't really been myself lately.
You know, now that...
我只是最近有点迷失自我, 最近 我在
Trying to figure out who I am and
uh, just felt a little bit lost
试图弄清楚自己到底是谁
呃，只是觉得有点迷失
And then all of a sudden,
I see you dressed as me.
然后突然，
看到你穿得像我一样。
And it's been kinda...
这有点
It's a lot for me, too.
对我来说也有太多东西要消化了，我也一样
So how did uh...
那么你们..呃
you guys get together?
是怎么走到一起的
How did this happen?
这到底发生了什么
I swear, I heard
Mjölnir call to me.
我发誓，我听到了 Mjonir 的呼唤
Ah, did it?
呃 真的吗
And so I came to investigate and...
所以我就来调查了 然后
- Pieces started glowing and swirling...
- Crazy.
- 碎片开始发光，环绕
- 这太疯狂了
Thor.
然后就成为雷神了
Well, you know what. It looks
good on you. It works, so...
恩，你知道吗，这装备在你身上看上去很不错，挺合适的
Just checking.
我只是试试
See you later.
一会儿见
What?
怎么了
We were just talking.
就只是正常交谈而已
Mom, don't leave me.
Mom, 别离我而去
Don't be afraid.
别害怕
Even when I'm gone, honey.
亲爱的，就算我离开了
You won't be alone.
你也不会感到孤单的
And whatever happens...
无论发生了什么
Never stop fighting.
永远不要停止战斗
- Hey.
- You alright?
- 嘿
- 你还好吗？
Great!
好极了
The sink would say otherwise.
水槽可不这么认为
You think I really
should be coming?
你觉得我真应该来吗？
I'm not getting any better.
我的病没有半点好转
You're a Thor.
Of course, you should come.
你是雷神，你肯定得来呀
Besides, what else
are you gonna do?
不来的话，你也没其他事儿可做
You're a Viking now.
你现在是维京人了
Means you pretty much
have to die in battle.
意味着你不得不战死杀场了
It needs to be
devastatingly painful.
还得是个惨烈的牺牲
Otherwise, you
don't get into Valhalla.
否则，你就不能去到瓦尔哈拉了
My plan.
我是这么计划的
What about you
kinging and stuff?
那你国王的那些职责呢
I love being king.
我喜欢当国王
I love my people.
我爱我的子民
But it's all meeting
and raven mail.
但一天全是些例会，和乌鸦邮件
And meetings that could
have been raven mail.
和那些本应是乌鸦邮件的例会
I miss fighting.
我想念战斗
I miss my sisters.
我想念我的战友姐妹们
Which is why you need to come.
所以你就更应该来了
Because I need Thor.
因为我需要一个
- Okay, we should go.
- Hmm, packed.
- 好了，我们该出发了
- 嗯, 收拾好了吗
Are you packed?
你收拾好了吗
Yes.
好
A hand grenade?
手榴弹？
No, it's a portable speaker.
不，便携式扬声器
Let's go.
我们出发
If you don't mind keeping
the sink thing under wraps.
如果你不介意的话，水槽的事情请帮我保密
I got you.
没问题
My fellow Asgardians...
我的阿斯加德子民们
Wish us well.
祝福我们吧
For we shall travel with
the speed of Odin's ravens.
让我们以奥丁雀信的速度穿行
We will return with children.
我们会把孩子们带回来
Many children.
非常多的孩子
Then we should feast,
along the children.
然后我们该举办盛宴，跟孩子们一起（而不是吃小孩儿）
We do not do that anymore.
往日不堪回首
It was dark times.
那确实是我们的至暗时刻
Shameful time.
可耻的时代
Okay, we should go.
好了，我们还是出发吧
So...
Still rollerblading?
还滑旱冰吗
No, no.
You?
不了，你还滑？
Oh yeah, every weekend.
滑呀，每个周末
Once you blade, you never fade.
一日旱冰人，一世旱冰魂
- Right, Korg?
- Skate twins for life.
- 对吧， Korg？
- 旱冰二人组一辈子！
Hey, can I run something by you?
嘿， 我能请教你点问题吗
Yeah.
可以呀
So I was thinking,
when we get to the bad guy...
我正在想，当我们遇到坏人时
What about if I had, like,
the cool catchphrase, like...
我是不是应该有个酷炫的口号什么的，就像
"Eat this hammer, bang!"
“吃这一锤 bang！”
Or like?
或者是
"Check out my hammer, boom!"
“看我锤子的厉害， Boom！”
Like, what about?
又或者是
You know,
I'm workshopping it.
你知道的， 我还在构思当中
No, they... They're all
really good. Mine is uh...
不用担心，他们都挺棒的，我的口号是
"This ends here and now."
“这将到此为止了”
Oh, that's such a good one.
哦，多好的一个
Took me a long
time to perfect it.
花了我好长时间才完善的
You'll get there.
You just need to practice.
你会想到最满意的，你只是需要多多练习
This is my first bad guy.
这将是我面对的第一个反派
You never forget your first.
第一个总是印象深刻 对吧
Yeah.
是呀
So you got a girlfriend?
那么 你有女朋友了吗
Oh, no, no.
没 没 没
Too busy. Don't have time.
You know, just...
太忙了，没时间，你知道的
With work and everything.
只光顾着工作之类的了
Cool.
酷
Let me check this place out.
我去看看周围情况
So cool.
太酷了
- Who's so cool?
- Huh?
- 谁太酷了
The buildings are cool.
这些建筑太酷了
What's happening there?
刚刚发生什么了
- What?
- Am I, uh...
- 什么什么
- 是不是你
Sensing feelings?
你对简 还有感觉呀
Feelings, what?
With Jane?
什么感觉，跟简吗
- Yeah.
- No, don't be ridiculous with feelings.
- 是呀
- 不可能，别犯傻了
The last time we had feelings
were long time ago. Long, long gone.
上次有感觉，那都是老久之前了
Not even...
She said you had feelings.
早就没感觉了, 还是你有感觉吗
Mate, relax.
We're on the same team.
放松点儿，伙计
我们是一队的
I know exactly what
team we're on, okay.
我知道，我们是哪队的好吧
Team Jane.
简队
Thing about Thor is that
he always bounces back.
索尔一定会来的
Like when Hela stole his
hammer, he went and built an ax
就像上次海拉摧毁了他的锤子后，他就去造了个斧头
which is forcing
the heart of a dying star.
由一颗垂死行星的心脏能量铸成
And with the same ax,
he used to cut off Thano's head.
也是砍掉萨诺斯脑袋的战斧
Oh, ho, ho, ho.
Now, come on.
What a neat story.
多么简练的故事呀
Oh, with all this talk
about chopping off heads...
说到砍下头颅
I wanna have a go.
我也来讲一个
What's this?
这是什么
Oh...
Oh, ho, ho, ho, ho...
Oh.
This is Harpy.
这是哈皮
Hello, Harpy.
你好呀 哈皮
How are you?
你好吗
Do you know
what Harpy loves?
你们知道哈皮喜欢什么吗
Having his head ripped off.
喜欢它的头被拧下来
What? You like it,
a second ago.
咋了呀，刚才你们不还挺喜欢这情节的吗
Alright.
Alright, alright.
好吧 好吧
Harpy's gone.
哈皮死了
Come on.
Sh, sh, sh, sh, sh.
Ah, you.
哈，你
I knew a little girl,
just like you.
我认识个小女孩，跟你挺像的
And she was brave.
And she was smart...
她也勇敢，她还聪明
And funny.
还幽默
And, she liked to draw.
而且她还喜欢画画
Let me ask you a question...
让我问你们个问题
About gods.
关于神明
They're meant
to protect you, right?
他们本应该保护你们的 对吧
Well, where are they?
那么，他们在哪呢
- Thor is on his way.
- Yeah!
- 雷神正在赶过来
- 是的
Yes...
好
I'm counting on that.
我就指望着他快来呢
That's why you're here.
也是把你们放这儿的原因
It's invitation only, so we're gonna
have to keep a low profile and blend in.
只有受邀人能进入，所以我们得低调点混入。
Luckily, disguises are my speciality.
幸运的是，我可是个伪装专家
Philosopher.
哲学家
It's all a painting.
弄来了这些
What are those?
这些是什么
Actual disguises.
真正的伪装
They're the cloaks of
the emotion gods.
这些是情感之神的斗篷
Every color signifies
different emotions.
每一种颜色代表着不同的情绪
- Where are the emotion gods?
- Hm, don't ask.
- 情感之神在哪呢？
- 呃 别问了
Welcome to the Golden Temple, kids.
欢迎来到黄金殿，孩子们
This is where the most powerful
creator gods in the universe hang out.
这就是所有最强大的创世神们玩耍的地方
That's the god of magic.
那是魔法之神
God of dreams.
梦境之神
God of carpentry.
匠神
Ah, look at that one.
看这个呀
Ah, yes.
That's Bao, god of dumplings.
啊，对
这是包， 饺子之神
- Hey, Bao.
- Bao!
Look up there, guys!
大家 看上面那儿
The Kronan god,
Ninny of the Nonny.
我族的克罗南之神， 妮妮闹妮
Hey, Ninny Nonny.
嘿， 妮妮闹妮
Zeus!
宙斯
Hey!
Hail Zeus!
宙斯万岁
Welcome.
For honoring me.
The man, the myth, the legend.
这个男人就是个神话，传说
Oh, I don't know if you know this,
but I based a lot of what I do on this guy.
你知道吗，我所作的很多事情都是效仿他的
He's got lightning and thunder.
Huge source of inspiration.
他有闪电 我是雷鸣， 可给了我巨大的灵感来源
That's really good.
那真是不错
You should lead with that
when you ask him for an army.
也许等你一会儿向他借兵的时候，可以用这段话开头，
Um, how do we get up there?
呃 我们该怎么去到前面呀
We should like, fly?
我们该飞过去吗？
Well, we can't interrupt him
in the middle of his entrance.
我们不能在他入场时打断他
He's famous
for all of us.
即使是对我们来说，他也是名人
Thunderbolt.
霹雳
- Thunderbolt.
- Yes!
Zeus!
Calm down!
冷静
Now, then...
静一静
I hereby open...
我特此召开
this holy council of the gods.
这个神圣的众神会议
Where we have many,
many serious matters...
来讨论下非常多的
To be talked about.
重大事件
Such as...
譬如说
Where are we going to
hold this year's orgy?
我们今年的高潮狂欢要在哪里举行呢
Is this guy for real?
这家伙是认真的吗
Honestly, I'm not mad at it.
说实话，我都有点习惯了
- I'm sure he has it covered, okay?
- Shh!
- 我确定他会说到屠神事件的
- 嘘！
- And now we're going to announce...
- Sorry.
- 而现在我们将要公布..
- 抱歉
The winner of the most human souls
sacrificed in the name of a god.
以神之名义献祭了最多人类灵魂的第一名是
Yeah, okay.
Maybe, he's not that great.
好吧，可能他确实没有那么优秀
Oh, no,
not good.
不 不
也太糟糕了
No, I don't think it's going
to get any better than this.
是呀 我不认为他们还会有什么比这更好的事情公布了
And at least,
god's army can help
听着, 这些神是不会帮我们的
But that thunderbolt,
I think that might be huge.
但那把霹雳神器，我认为还是能帮上很大忙的
Judges!
Jane, you go right.
Thor, you go left.
简走右边
索尔走左边
We bum-rush him,
take the bolt, ding dong.
我们肉蛋冲击，把他定在墙里，带走神器，叮咚完工
- All right, let's go get it.
- No, no, no, no, no.
- 好，我们行动吧
- 不 不 不
There's no ding donging
or bum-rushing.
没有叮咚，或者肉蛋冲击
Especially not, Zeus's bum.
尤其可不能是宙斯的肉蛋
When the time is right,
I'm gonna talk to him.
待时机成熟，我会跟他谈谈的
Time is right now.
现在就是成熟的时机
- Time is not right now.
- Who is talking?
- 现在可不成熟
- 谁说话呢
Who is talking?!
谁说话呢?!
- These guys!
- Korg, shut up.
- 这几位！
- 快闭嘴 Korg
You guys have something
to say to the group?
你们有什么话要跟大家说吗
Sorry.
抱歉
I'm bashing heads in
60 seconds, so speak fast.
我60秒后就要狂干一场了, 所以, 有话快说
Literally, heads will roll.
真的, 脑袋会到处滚的那种
Who are you two?
你俩到底是谁
Hello!
您好
Uh, let me be the first to say
it is an honor and a privilege...
呃，我先说这是我的荣幸来...
- to be here.
- No, I can't hear you.
- 来到这里
- 不， 我们听不清
Why don't you take the stage?
你为什么不来台上说
The stage, down there?
台上, 下面那个吗？
Well, yes. You see the area
that looks very much like a stage?
呃，对的，你看到这块区域了吗，就像个舞台一样的地方
Gotcha.
收到
Oops, sorry.
抱歉
Good luck, bro!
祝你好运，兄弟
Mighty Zeus!
Heh, wow!
伟大的宙斯
Gods of the universe.
宇宙诸神
I come here to ask for help,
to raise an army.
我来这里寻求你们的帮助
来组建一支军队
There's a maniac, called the God
Butcher, which seeks to end us all.
有个神精病，叫屠神者，誓要将诸神杀尽
Destruction is everywhere.
混乱到处都是
Entire planets, realms, have
been left completely unprotected.
一个个星球，神域，都没了神的庇护
There's nothing but
chaos in his way.
他所到之处混乱不堪
But I know where he is.
但我知道他的藏身之处
With your help...
在您的帮助下...
We can crush him before
he kills anyone else.
我们能在他屠戮更多人之前，将他一举击溃
That guy.
那家伙呀
He killed a couple
of low-level gods.
他只不过杀了几个低等级的神
Eh, boo-hoo.
多大的事儿呀
If that's all, pretty boy...
如果就是因为这，帅哥...
You go back to your seat
and you be quiet.
回到你座位上，别再出声了
Um, yeah, I'm sorry. Did you not
hear any of what I just said?
呃，我没听错把，你是没听到我刚说的话吗
He's, he's murdering on mass.
他正在大规模屠杀呢
I tell you, one time.
我再说一次
Now, you shut up.
你先闭嘴
You'll be quiet.
你给我安静
Because you are this close
to being uninvited to the orgy.
因为就差这么一点点，我就要不邀请你到高潮狂欢了
Zeus!
We must do something.
宙斯，我们必须要做点什么
You can not come to the orgy!
你肯定不会收到高潮派对的邀请了
You have to listen to us.
你必须得听我们的
Sit down!
给我坐下
Your highness. Whenever
you're ready, you just tell me.
殿下，什么时候准备好了，我就出手
We go on my signal.
等我信号
What is the signal?
什么信号
- It'll be go.
- Hmm...
信号是 “上”
Let's see who you are.
让我们来看看你到底是谁
Take off your disguise.
卸掉你的伪装
And flick!
我弹
Flicked too hard, damn it!
你弹太大力了 该死
Should we help him?
我们该上去帮忙吗
Eventually.
最终会的
Grape?
葡萄？
Looks like a shy...
看着像是害羞造成的..
And what about the others?
其他人呢？
- We take off their disguise too.
- Oh, no, you don't. We got this.
- 要不要我也卸下你们的伪装
- 天呐 不要，我们自己卸
- Disguise off.
- Mine's off.
- 伪装没了
- 我的也卸了
Asgardians...
阿斯加德人...
I thought you've seen the
last of him when Odin died.
我还以为奥丁死时他的后代也跟着灭绝了
You...
are Thor.
你是索尔
The God of Thunder.
雷神
There is no thunder?
但我也没看到闪电呀？
Just the sound of lightning?
就只有几声轻雷而已
Good jab, dad!
说的漂亮，老爸！
Zeus, this is bigger than this.
宙斯，这事关重大
He's taken Asgardian children.
他掠走了阿斯加德的孩子们
Who do you think we are?
你以为我们是谁呀
The God police?
神界警察吗
Every god watches
over their own people.
每个神都看管他自己的国度和人民
Nothing more,
nothing less.
不多也不少
Asgardian problems...
阿斯加德的麻烦
are Asgardian problems.
是阿斯加德的麻烦
How the mighty have fallen.
伟人怎么就这么堕落了
My hero, Zeus...
我的英雄，宙斯
Afraid.
害怕了
Couple of things...
几件事情
One.
Yes, I am scared.
第一，是的，我是害怕了
Gorr has the Necrosword.
Gorr 手里有死灵之剑
Which means, he will kill us.
意味着他是能杀死我们的
Not good.
这可不好
Two, I know you're trying
to do the right thing.
第二，我知道你试图做正确的事情
I understand.
我能理解
But all you do,
is causing panic.
但你现在所作的，只不过是引起恐慌
Panic is not good.
恐慌可不好
We are safe here.
我们在这里很安全
You, my friend.
你，我的朋友
You are safe here.
你在这很安全
So chill up here, okay?
所以在这里放轻轻松，好吧？
Have some wine. Have some grape.
喝点酒，吃点葡萄
Anything goes here...
全能宫殿里发生的
In Omnipotent City.
不会外传
Three, don't talk back to Zeus.
第三，别跟宙斯顶嘴
If you do that,
I put your clothes back on.
如果你这样做，我就把你衣服变回来
Now, I put your clothes back on.
现在，我变回你的衣服
Flick, flick, flick.
It's the Golden Temple of the Gods.
我弹
这可是众神的黄金殿
It's not a rude
and nudy Twister.
可不是什么粗俗的裸体盛宴
If you're not gonna help us,
then at least, let us use your weapons.
就算你不打算帮我们，至少借你的武器给我们
We need your lightning bolt.
我们需要你的闪电神器
My lightning bolt is
called Thunderbolt.
我的神器名叫霹雳
So I think, to use somebody's
secret weapon like this...
如果你要跟别人借他的秘密武器
That you should, at least, get
the name right when you ask.
至少 在借的时候也把它名字说对了
Can I borrow Thunderbolt?
能借您的霹雳一用吗
Thunderbolt!
霹雳
No.
不借
Do not worry.
别担心
The God Butcher...
屠神者..
He will not reach Eternity.
他是不会到达永恒的
Eternity?
永恒？
What does he mean,
"reach Eternity"?
他说的 “到达永恒” 是什么意思？
Oh, shit!
哦，糟糕
Eternity.
永恒
It's a very powerful being at
the center of the universe.
是一个无比强大的存在，身处宇宙的中心
He will grant the desire of
the first person who reaches it.
传说他会满足第一个到达他那的人的任何愿望
Like a wishing well?
像个许愿井吗？
What do you think a guy called,
the God Butcher, would wish for?
你认为一个叫屠神者的人会有什么愿望呢
If he seeks the altar of Eternity,
that means he could wipe us out at once.
如果他想办法去到了永恒，他很可能一次性抹除我们全部
- Zeus, we must act now.
- He's not going to make it.
- 宙斯，我们必须得出手了
- 他不可能办到的
He doesn't have the key.
他没有钥匙
Is this the
purpose of the gods?
这就是神的使命吗
To hide away in a
golden palace, like cowards?
躲藏在金色圣殿之中，像群胆小鬼一样
Maybe we have lost our way.
也许我们已经堕落了
You know what?
We're gonna stop him ourselves.
知道吗，我们还是自己去阻止他吧
I am afraid,
I cannot allow that.
恐怕我不会允许你们这么做
This is a secret place,
这儿是个秘密的地点
known only to the gods.
只有神明才知道
You know where we are...
你知道我们的位置
The God Butcher could use you...
屠神者可以利用你
To find us.
来找到我们
This is not good.
这可不好
So now...
那么现在，
You must stay.
你们必须留下
Guards!
护卫！
Hey!
嘿！
Can we do
my plan now?
我们能换你的计划了吗
Yes,
rush his bum.
是的， 给我冲烂他屁股
Hell, yeah!
Oy,
you didn't say "go".
嘿 你还没发 “上” 的信号呢
Coming, guys.
来了, 伙计们
Thor, catch!
索尔，接着！
Korg!
Val, duck!
Val，躲
Korg!
Thor.
Oh, no.
No!
Korg!
不
Thor!
I'm perishing.
我正在瓦解
Zeus!
You're next, Odinson!
你就是下一个，奥丁之子
That's the sound of the Viking.
这就是雷电的声音
No.
Korgy!
Thor, I'm down here.
我在下面呢
Great! Where are you?
So I can get dressed for a lovely ball.
太好了，你在哪？
- Here I am.
- Korgy!
- 这儿呢
I was about to die.
我以为你死了
Yes!
You're alive!
太好了，你竟然还活着
Turns out, the only part of
the Kornan that's alive is its mouth.
原来，科南族唯一活着的部位就只是他们的嘴
Korgy, listen.
I need you to call the goats.
听着， Korg, 我需要你召唤山羊
I'll do my best.
我尽力
- My god, I need you alive.
- I won't mind.
- 给我用生命保护他
- 我会的
Ready to go for a ride?
准备好旅行了吗
Now,
you got me six.
现在, 你能看到我的盲角了
Eight o'clock, Val.
8点钟方向
7:48!
You can do it, man.
Just give it a...
你能做到的，再加把劲
That's not it.
不对
Nope.
不
Come on, Korg.
Purse those lips.
加把劲 Korg
嘴唇用力
I did it!
我做到了
And then the goat boat came in,
rescued us, and we flew out the window.
然后，山羊彩虹船冲入，救走我们飞出窗外
The end.
落幕
Another classic Thor adventure.
又一个经典的索尔冒险
Can't believe you killed Zeus.
真难以置信你杀死了宙斯
Well, you know what they say...
你知道人们说的那句老话
Never meet your heroes.
永远不要去见你的英雄
What's important is, we are on
our way to you, right now.
重要的是，我们正在赶来救你们的路上
How are you guys doing?
Are you okay?
你们怎么样了，还好吗
We're alright.
A little scared.
还好，就是有点害怕
Well, listen. I know what
it's like to be scared.
听着，我知道恐惧是什么感觉
And I'll tell you,
when I was your age...
我要告诉你们，当我还是你们年纪的时候
I don't think I would
have been as brave as you.
我不认为我比你们更勇敢
Really?
真的吗
In fact, you might just be the
bravest Asgardians that I've ever met.
事实上，你们可能是我见过最勇敢的阿斯加德人了
All of you.
你们全部都是
So I need you to keep
being brave, alright?
所以， 我需要你们继续保持勇敢，好吗？
And take care of each other.
You're a team now.
互相照顾，你们现在是一个团队了
Team kids in a cage.
笼中被困孩子队
Can you do that?
能做到吧
Yeah.
I think we can do that.
嗯
我想应该可以吧
I know you can.
我知道你们可以的
Alright?
好了
- Thor?
- Yeah?
- 索尔？
- 什么事
I'm glad, I met my hero.
我很高兴我遇到了我的英雄
Wow.
Thanks, buddy.
谢谢，伙计
How are the children?
孩子们怎么样了
As you can imagine, they're a
little bit scared because they're kids.
你也能想象到，他们有点害怕，因为他们还是孩子
But I told him that
everything is going to plan.
但我告诉他们一切都在依照计划进行
And so you lied to them.
所以你对他们说谎了
You still have a plan?
你还有计划吗
- Yes, there's a plan.
- There's no plan.
- 是的，有计划
- 根本就没有计划了
- There is a plan.
- No, there's no plan.
- 有计划
- 没有
We failed to raise a god army.
我们要组建神军的计划失败了
- Korg is dead.
- He's not dead.
- Korg 还牺牲了
- 他没牺牲
- I'm not dead.
- Well, he's a head.
- 我没死呀
- 那他也就剩个头了
And you, you were properly humilated.
还有你，你刚刚才被彻底的羞辱了一番
No, I got properly naked,
which I'm okay with.
没有，我只是被彻底脱光了而已，我感觉没啥大不了的
- Jane?
- I was okay with it.
- 简？
- 我也OK
- Korg?
- I loved it.
- 我爱了
We're not going into the Shadow Realm
weaker than we were before. We...
我们不能比之前还弱的进入暗域，我们
- We're gonna die.
- No one's gonna die.
- 我们很可能有去无回的
- 我们不会去送死的
- We...
- Okay.
Everything is fine.
We did great back there.
一切都还好， 我们刚刚已经干得很棒了
- We killed Zeus.
- You killed Zeus.
- 我们杀了宙斯
- 你杀了宙斯
For you, that may or may not
be catastrophic for the whole universe.
为你们，有可能会成为整个宇宙的灾难
And surely,
毋庸置疑的
The entire god kingdom is probably gonna
hunt us down for the rest of our days.
整个众神国度恐怕要从此追捕我们直至余生了
But listen, you stole
this beautiful weapon.
但是听着，我们抢来了这个美丽的雷霆神器
Alright, this is the army right here.
看吧，它本身就是一个军队
It's sleek, it's slender,
it's powerful, it's beautiful.
它润滑，纤细，它强大，又美丽
Well, for you, I love it.
那个，对你来说，我是为你获得了它
For you, Valkyrie.
而高兴，女武神
I mean, it's not
really what I'm into.
我意思是，这不是我顺手的武器
But I got my,
my weapon out there.
我已经拥有了我的武器了，在那边
Can I borrow that for a sec?
能借我用下这个吗
Ah!
There you are, old friend.
你在这儿呀，老朋友
That was quite
an entrance, back there.
之前的冲入神殿还真是个漂亮的入场呐
This and that.
听着 呃
We good?
我们没问题吧
Yeah?
是吧？
I mean, I don't feel weird having
my ax weapon around, but come on.
我是指 我在旧锤面前可没感觉到别扭，但真的别闹了
Mjölnir, in the past.
Mjonir, 那已经是过去时了
It's you and me now, buddy.
现在是你跟我了 老铁
You know what?
那什么
I think it's time
for your first beer.
我觉得是时候给你来上第一口啤酒了
What do you say?
你怎么说
Delicious.
好喝吧
I'm sorry we've been fighting lately.
对不起 我们最近一直在闹脾气
Hey.
嘿
Oh, hey.
哦，嘿
It's quite the...
view, huh?
这景色很棒吧
Yeah, it's beautiful.
是呀，这也太美了
As I was saying, I was very, very
impressed with what you did back there.
刚刚我还说到，你在金殿上的发挥真是让我印象深刻呀
You and Mjölnir.
你和 Mjonir
Yeah.
是呀
- In space, there are dolphins.
- What?
- 在太空中，有海豚
- 怎么可能
This...
You should see
some space dolphins.
你应该能看到一些太空海豚
Beautiful.
美极了
- God.
- They're so beautiful, so rare,
- 天呐
- 他们美吧，还非常罕见
They're very loyal creatures.
他们是非常忠诚的生物
They're made for life...
他们一生都只忠于自己的伴侣...
In packs of 6.
们大概一组6头的样子
♫ Oh, brother.
Man, you look so hot ♫
🎵 哦，兄弟，你看上去太性感了
♫ I wanna get in your rock ♫
🎵 我想要进入你的石头
♫ When we get together,
we're gonna get it on ♫
🎵 当我们在一起时，我们就直入主题
♫ I'm gonna make some babies ♫
🎵 我要给你生小石头
That is the song that my dad sang to
my other dad when they were courting.
那是我爸爸唱给另一个爸爸的歌 在他们交合的时候
When two Kronans want to make a baby,
they get together inside a mountain.
当两个克罗南人想要小孩的时候，他们会进入到山中
They go down to
a little lava pool.
去到一个小熔岩池边
They hold hands
over the hot lava.
在滚烫岩浆上双手紧握
And then after a month,
然后一个月之后
They pull their hands apart...
他们双手分开...
and they finally created a
beautiful new Kronan baby boy.
然后他们就创造出了一个美丽的克罗南男婴
Oh, it's fascinating.
And hot.
这不是很迷人吗
还很性感
Did you ever had
a special someone?
你曾有过特别的人吗?
Oh, I've had...
哦，我有过
many special someones.
很多特别的人
But, I don't know.
但是，我不知道
I don't know if I want it again.
我不确定 那还是我想要的了
Is that because you lost your girlfriend
in battle and never forgave yourself?
是不是因为在战场上失去了女朋友之后便一直原谅不了自己
And now, you're just trying to find
the answers in the bottom of the bottle.
而现在你也只是在最糟糕的情况下努力寻找答案
And some meaningless goings-on,
which only serves to numb the pain.
而一些无关痛痒的恋情也只有暂时缓解疼痛的作用
Instead of bringing you
real happiness or satisfaction.
而取代不了真正的幸福和成就感
Yeah, something like that.
是啊, 差不多
They're beautiful.
他们很美丽
Beautiful thing.
美丽的东西
Jane.
简
- What?
- I want to feel shitty about you.
- 什么事?
- 我想因你而感到糟糕
What?
什么?
For me, I want...
那个
I...
我
I want to feel shitty
about something.
我想再次因为什么事情而感到糟糕
I think that's you.
我认为就你
- Not really getting attached.
- Not as attached.
- 我还是没搞懂
- 不是那意思 该死
Well, uh...
额
My friend, he told me that
it was better to feel shitty
我朋友告诉我, 再次有感觉即使是糟糕的感觉也是件好事情
for losing love than it is
to never experience love,
就算会失去的爱也比从未感受过爱强
and to feel nothing at all, and
feel empty and I think he was right.
比没任何感受内心空荡要强, 我认为他是对的
Which is how I've been
feeling for a long time.
也是我一直以来的内心感觉, 有好长一段时间了
I push people away,
kept them at a distance
我跟人们保持距离,
because of the fear of that loss.
因为我害怕会失去
But I don't want to do that anymore.
但我现在不想继续这样了
No, no, no.
是呀,
Close off your heart
will seal the pain.
关闭你的内心以为可以封印伤痛
That's what I did.
那就是我做的
Yes, I closed off my
heart and I meditated.
是的, 我关闭我的内心去冥想
- You meditate?
- No, it's so boring.
- 你也冥想吗?
- 不 ,那太无聊了
It actually made
me more angry.
是呀, 反而让我更加焦躁
But I'm tired of giving
myself up as the idea of fate
但是我已经厌倦放弃自我交给所谓命运
and try to figure out what
the universe wants from me.
去瞎琢磨宇宙要传达给我的使命了
I want to live in the moment.
我只想活在当下
I wanted to live like
there's no tomorrow.
我想把每天都活的像最后一天
Throw caution to the wind.
把担心和犹豫都抛之脑后
I want...
I want to be with you, Jane.
我想要
我想要和你在一起
What do you say?
你怎么想的
I have cancer.
我得了癌症
I'm sorry, what?
抱歉, 你说啥
I'm dying.
我快死了
- Wait, what is happening?
- God!
- 等下, 发生了什么
- 天呐
- I...
- No, no, no, no.
- 我
- 不 不 不
Jane, Jane, Jane, Jane.
简
- Wait, Jane.
- What did I say?
- 等下, 简
- 我说了什么
I didn't mean that.
我不是认真的
Just kidding.
只是开玩笑的
I...
我
don't have cancer.
没有癌症
I want to smash something.
我只想要锤爆些东西
Jane, I'm so sorry.
简, 我太抱歉了
Don't be sorry.
别感到内疚
When did you find out?
什么时候发现的
Um...
About six months ago.
I...
大概六个月前, 我
I was just feeling tired.
只是感觉到疲惫
And then, they told
me I have stage four.
然后他们告诉我已经第四阶段了
Get my fears in order.
我处理好自己的恐惧
And then, I heard Mjölnir
calling me and so...
然后我就听到了 Mjonir 的呼唤
I thought, maybe...
我想, 如果
If science didn't help,
then maybe...
科学帮不上忙, 也许
Viking space magic.
维京的星际魔法
And that's why you came to New Asgard.
于是我就来新阿斯加德了
Yeah, I think the hammer...
是呀, 我认为锤子
Knew what would
be good for me and...
应该知道对我来说什么是更好的
Maybe not.
但也许它也不清楚
Jane, none of us know how long we have.
简, 我们没人知道自己还有多久能活
You don't know
what tomorrow holds.
你不知道明天会发生什么
And Mjölnir,
Mjölnir chose you.
而 Mjonir
Mjonir选择了你
It chose you because
you are worthy.
它选中你是因为你有资格
And that's something.
那是了不起的
When I first met you,
I was unworthy...
当我刚遇到你的时候, 我不配拥有神力
I was unable to
pick up my hammer.
我没能力拿起我的锤子
You told me, there was no greater purpose
than to help those in need.
你告诉过我, 没有什么比帮助那些身处困境之人更具有意义的了
You made me worthy.
是你将我变成有资格的雷神
So whatever you wanna do,
we can do together.
所以不管你想要做什么, 我们都一起完成
Look, what do you wanna do?
你现在想做什么
I'm gonna get those
children back to their families.
我只想把孩子们救回家
I want to finish that mission.
我想完成这个任务
Spoken like a true Thor.
这才像是个真正的雷神
How do you feel now?
现在你感觉如何
So scared.
非常害怕
How do you feel?
你感觉如何
Shitty.
糟糕
How shitty?
多糟糕?
Really shitty.
糟糕透了
I wonder what those two
are talking about, out there.
我琢磨这俩人在外面说啥呢
Yeah, they're not talking.
是呀, 他们可没用说的
Oh!
哦!
Do you think those two will ever
hold hands over a hot lava pool
你认为那俩人相信 在熔岩池旁双手紧握
to make a Thor baby?
会造出小雷神吗
Unlikely, sadly.
恐怕够呛了, 令人难过
Oh, that's too bad.
哦, 那太可惜了
I think Thor would make a great dad.
我认为索尔会是个不错的父亲
Hey!
We're here.
嘿! 我们到了.
This is where color goes.
没有色彩了
They're not here.
孩子们不在这
Where are they?
他们在哪呢
The hell is this place?
这是什么鬼地方
Bifrost is the key.
彩虹桥才是钥匙
It's a trap!
这是个陷阱
Can you tell me why you just threw
Stormbreaker out the window?
你能告诉我你为什么把风暴战斧撇出窗外吗
He needs it to open the gates of Eternity.
他需要它开启永恒之门
We really have to
stop meeting like this.
你可别又靠我这么近了
Call the ax.
召唤斧子
I'll call the ax when
you call the dentist.
你召唤牙医, 我就召唤战斧
Call the ax.
召唤斧子
Tell me where the children
are or I'm gonna kill...
告诉我孩子们在哪, 要不然我就杀..
Call the ax.
召唤斧子
How ungodly you are.
你还真是不称职的神呀
You know nothing
你对当神
of being a god.
啥都不懂
You went to the gods for help
你找神求助
and they did nothing.
而他们却袖手旁观
We're alike, in that sense.
我们从某些角度还挺像的
He's nothing like you.
他跟你可不像
What was that?
你说什么
I said, he's nothing like you.
我说, 他跟你一点儿都不像
That's right.
I'm not a hypocrite.
是呀, 我可不是伪君子
I'm truly creating peace.
我是真真切切的在创造和平
You're murdering innocent gods.
你在屠杀无辜神明
Innocent?
无辜?
Are you a Valkyrie?
你是女武神吧
Huh?
是
Haha, how exciting.
哈, 多让人感到兴奋呀
Oh, my gosh.
They're onto you too.
哦 天呐, 他们连你也辜负了
Your sisterhood was led to slaughter.
你的姐妹们都被叫去挡枪遭残忍杀害了
Did you pray to the gods...
那时候你祈求神明了吗
When the women you loved
laid dying on the battlefield?
当你深爱的女人躺在战场上死去的时候
Did you beg them for help...
你祈求神的帮助了吗
As your family was massacred?
当你的家人遭受屠杀的时候?
Good chat.
很好的聊天
This one...
这一个
You're interesting.
你很有趣
You're different.
你不一样
Yes.
是呀
Awh...
嗷...
You're dying.
你快死了
I'm sorry.
真抱歉
We're on the same path.
我们在一条船上
Just as the sword empowered me.
正如死灵剑给了我力量
The hammer empowered you.
锤子给了你力量一样
But it did nothing
to change your fate.
但它没对你的命运做半点儿改变
The gods will use you...
神们只会利用你
But they will not help you.
而不会帮助你
There is no...
根本就不存在
eternal reward...
永恒的奖励
for us.
给我们
She'll be gone soon.
她很快就要离开了
And you know who won't help her?
你知道什么对她没任何帮助吗
I give you one guess.
只给你一次猜的机会
I know your pain.
我理解你的痛苦
Love is pain.
爱是伤痛
I had a daughter once.
我曾有个女儿
I put my faith in a higher power,
hoping it will save her.
我寄希望于更高的神力, 能来救救她
And she...
而她就这么
died.
死了
Now I understand...
现在我弄明白了
My daughter is the lucky one.
我女儿才是那个幸运的
She does not have to grow up in a world...
她不再需要在一个充满了苦难的
Of suffering and pain
由邪恶的神掌管的世界里
run by wicked gods.
长大并遭罪了
Choose love.
选择爱吧
Call the ax.
召唤斧子
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- 你还好吗?
- 还好
Hmm, I want to kill that guy.
我想要杀了那家伙
So do I, but we have
to take him alive.
我也想, 但是我们得留他活口
He's our only link to
finding those children.
只有他知道孩子们在哪
Oh!
Thank you, Mr. Goat.
哦! 谢谢你, 羊先生
Val!
We gotta get her out of here.
我们得把她带离这里
I got you.
没事儿了 我来了
The goats are here.
Come on, let's go.
羊来了, 我们走
Stormbreaker, take us home.
风暴, 带我们回家
Look, there are other, more aggressive
forms of treatment we can try,
我们还有其他的更激进一些的治疗形式可以尝试
but something's affecting her
body's ability to fight the cancer.
但有些东西正在影响着她自身对抗癌症的能力
I'm sorry, Thor.
我们非常抱歉, 索尔
Oh, there you are.
哦 你在这儿呀
What's going on out there?
刚外面发生了什么
Oh, some moron made a fridge
without a door. Can you believe it?
哦, 一些白痴做了个没有门的冰箱, 你敢信?
Don't you worry, I got it open
and got you all sorts of goodies.
别担心, 被我打开了, 给你弄了这些好东西
How's Val?
Val 怎么样了?
Oh, she's in a lot of pain,
uh, but she is stable.
哦, 她很痛苦 额 但是也稳定下来了
Okay, good.
那就好
Now, I just gotta get this...
现在, 我只是想把这些...
- out of my...
- Woah! No, no, no.
- 东西拔出...
- wow 停 别 别
That's gotta stay in there.
那些要继续插着
That's all the magic potions
and elixirs doing their thing, so...
那是所有魔法药剂行使它们的功效, 所以
Just gonna pop out for a moment.
我只去一会儿
Pick up the kids.
Uh, kill a bad guy.
带回孩子们, 杀个坏蛋
And then, I'll come straight back.
然后, 我就回来
You're going without me?
你要独自去面对他吗
Uh, yeah.
额 , 对
What happened to like...
doing everything together?
你刚才不还说要什么事都要一起面对的吗
He's gonna use those kids
to distract you.
他会利用孩子来分散你的注意力
You need me.
你需要我
I do need you, Jane.
我是需要你
I need you alive.
我需要你活着
Would be great to have
you on the battlefield.
有你在战场上确实很棒
Fighting Gorr side by side,
肩并肩对抗 Gorr
but that hammer is killing you.
但是锤子会杀死你的
Every time you use it,
it's draining all of your mortal strength,
每次你拿起锤子, 它都在损耗你的生命力
leaving your body unable
to fight the cancer.
使你无力再对抗癌症
What happened to live
like there's no tomorrow?
你不是说要活得像没有明天了一样吗
It was before I knew
you might not have one.
那是在我知道你可能真的没有明天之前才说的
Why not have
one more adventure?
为什么不再来次冒险呢?
Jane, if there's a chance to live.
You have to take it.
简. 就算有一丝生存的希望, 你也得抓住
Spoken like a true Thor
who does not have cancer.
说的像是个没得癌症的真正雷神
I know, I seem like some cool
astrophysicist from New Mexico.
我知道, 我听起来像个来自新墨西哥州的很酷的天体物理学家
Just living the dream.
只为活在梦里
But, look at me.
但是 看看我呀
I wanna keep fighting.
我想要继续战斗
I'm the Mighty Thor.
我可是全能的雷神
And you want me not to do that?
你却叫我不要那么做
What's the point of
more time than this?
浪费更多时间在病床上又有什么意义呢?
Because I love you.
因为我爱你
I've always loved you.
我一直爱着你
And this is a chance, for us.
而这是我们最后的希望
If you pick up that damn hammer
again, then that chance is gone.
如果你再次拿起那该死的锤子, 这希望就没了
It's your choice, Jane.
这是你的选择, 简
But I'd regret it,
every single day
但 我会遗憾终生的
If I didn't ask you to stay here, so we
can try and figure this out together.
如果我没有命令你留在病床上 让我们一起面对
You better come back to me.
你最好给我活着回来
I'm coming back,
as soon as I can.
我会第一时间回到你身边的
Break a leg.
打断他一条腿
I'll break all his legs.
我会打断他所有的腿
Remember that, the gate
to Eternity is at the literal center...
记住, 去往永恒的大门就在
- of the universe.
- Universe.
- 宇宙的字面中心处
- 宇宙
- You have to pass the comet.
- Yes.
- 你得穿过彗星带
- 好
Yes, yes. I know.
We've been over this.
好的 我知道了
我们提到过
I'm not going to get lost.
我不会迷路的
So how are you feeling
with the old stab wound?
你的背刺伤怎么样
- I think I lost my kidney
- Gone? Completely?
- 我感觉我的肾没了
- 一点儿都不剩了
I wish I could join you, but...
我希望我还能跟你一起战斗, 但是
I'd probably die and that
won't help get the kids back.
我很可能死, 还不会对救孩子有任何帮助
So you'll have
to go it alone.
所以你只能独自前往了
All you have to do,
is destroy that sword.
你唯一需要做的就是摧毁那把剑
It's his source of power.
那是他力量的来源
You won't survive
long without it.
没了剑 他活不了多久的
Hey, don't die.
嘿, 可别死了
Hell, no.
肯定不会
Eternity.
永恒
Finally.
终于要到了
Hi, kids.
嗨 孩子们
I knew you'd come.
我就知道你会赶来的
Go, kids.
快出去, 孩子们
Everyone okay?
都没事儿吧
Alright, gather round.
Gather round.
好的, 都聚过来
Good to see you, in person.
很高兴见到你们本人
'Scuse me.
高兴见到你
Alright, listen up!
Here's the plan.
好的, 都听着, 这将是我们的计划
We sneak our way towards Stormbreaker,
我们悄悄溜到风暴战斧边
Being very careful not to bump into,
any of those big shadow monsters.
要非常小心不要撞到那些巨大的影子怪物
They're behind me, aren't they?
他们就在我身后, 是吧？
Does anyone here
have battle experience?
这儿有人有过战斗经验的吗?
Well, no time to
learn like the present.
那就没时间现学了
But, we're not
strong like you.
但是我们没有你强壮呀
We're just kids.
我们还是孩子
Hey, don't forget.
You're Asgardian kids.
嘿, 别忘了, 你们可是阿斯加德的后裔
I'm not.
我不是
- I'm just a Lightfusion.
- And I'm a Ligathian kid.
- 我只是个Lightfusion.
- 而我只是个Ligathian小孩
Okay.
好吧 好吧
But today,
you're Asgardians.
但是今天, 你们都是阿斯加德人
Now, collect your weapons.
现在, 拿上你们的武器
What?
什么武器
Go and find anything
you can pick up.
都去找个任何能拿起来的东西在手里
And bring it back here.
然后带过来
Hurry, hurry.
快点 快点
They're getting closer,
hurry up.
它们越来越近了
动作都快点
Today, is a day that
will go down in history.
今天将是载入史册的一天
Today's a day they'll talk
about for generations to come.
今天将是被传颂历代的一天
Today, we are Space Vikings!
今天, 我们都是太空维京人
Present...
arms!
秀出你们的武器
Who should ever
hold these weapons
任何手持这些武器的人
and believes in going home
is a true of heart.
打心里相信并盼望回家的
And therefore,
worthy and shall possess...
都将是被选中之人
For a limited time only.
并在限定时间内拥有
The power of Thor!
雷神之力
General Axl...
将军 Axl
Lead your army
to that ax.
带领你的军队攻向风暴战斧
We shall do our work...
我们会尽我们的职责
For Asgard.
为了阿斯加德
Jane.
简
Destroy that sword
and he's dead.
摧毁那把剑, 他就会死
The gate is almost open.
You gotta stop Stormbreaker.
永恒之门即将打开, 你得赶紧想办法阻止风暴战斧
It's okay.
I got him.
没事儿的, 我能对付他
Stormbreaker, stop this!
风暴 快停下来!
Get a hold of yourself.
Look what you're doing.
振作点, 看看你都做了些什么呀
I'm gonna get you out of there.
我要把你从这儿弄出来
Come on!
加把劲
Let go of my friend!
放开我的朋友
You've lost, Lady Thor.
你就要输了, 雷神女士
First off,
首先
the name is Mighty Thor.
我名号乃 全能的雷神
Secondly...
第二
If you can't say Mighty Thor,
如果你说不出 全能雷神
I'll accept Dr. Jane Foster!
我也接受 简 福斯特 博士
Thirdly,
第三
eat my hammer!
吃我一锤
Stormbreaker!
风暴战斧
I knew you could do it.
我知道你能做到的
Axl!
Get them home.
Axl! 带他们回家
Jane?
简?
I'm okay.
我没事儿
You gotta stop him.
你得阻止他
Gorr, stop!
Gorr, 快停下
What kind of father
would I be, if I stopped.
我算是哪门子父亲, 如果我停下来
I know your pain,
but this isn't the way.
我懂你的痛苦, 但不能以这种方式解决
It's not death
or revenge that you seek.
死亡和复仇不是你诉求的
What do I seek?
那你说我在诉求什么
You seek love.
你在诉求爱
Love?
爱?
Why should I seek love?
我为什么要诉求爱?
Because that's all
any of us want.
因为那才是我们所有人追求的
How dare, you turn
your back on me.
你怎么胆敢背对我一走了之
You won, Gorr.
你赢了Gorr
Why would I spend my last moments
with you, when I can be with her?
为什么要在你身上浪费我最后的时间, 当我可以陪在简身边
I choose love.
我选择爱
You can, too.
You can bring her back.
你也还可以的, 你还有机会带回你女儿
Make your wish.
许你的愿吧
I'm dying.
我要死了
She would have no one.
她将会孤苦无依的
She would be alone.
她会孤零一人的
She won't be alone.
她不会孤独一人的
My love.
我亲爱的
I've missed you,
so much.
我好想你
太想你了
I've missed you, too.
我也想你
- I'm so sorry.
- It's okay.
- 我太抱歉了
- 没事儿了
As soon as I picked up that hammer...
当我拿起锤子的瞬间
It's like...
I've gotten an extra life.
就像是, 我又添了一条命
It's just...
真是太
Magical.
魔幻了
Not too bad for a human.
对一个凡人来说已经不错了吧
Not too bad for a god.
对一个神来说都已经足够棒了
I think I figured
out my catchphrase.
我终于想好我的口号了
- Really? What is it?
- Come closer.
- 真的吗? 是什么
- 靠近点
Perfect.
完美
- It's the best one yet.
- Thank you.
- 是迄今为止最好的一个
- 谢谢
Keep your heart open.
敞开你内心
I love you.
我爱你
I love you too.
我也爱你
Protect her.
保护她
Protect my love.
保护我的爱
Let me tell you the
legend of the Space Viking.
让我来给你们讲一个宇宙维京人的传奇
a.k.a
又名
"The Mighty Thor".
"全能的雷神"
a.k.a
又名
"Dr. Jane Foster".
"简. 福斯特 博士"
Her sacrifice saved the universe and
taught us all what it means to be worthy.
她的牺牲拯救了宇宙, 并教给了我们什么才叫做有意义的人生
She helped the
children of the gods.
她帮助神的孩子们
Who laser beamed
their way back home,
用激光传送回了
to their dozy, little fishing
village turned tourist destination.
他们那悠闲打鱼的被改造为旅游胜地的小村庄
Mommy!
妈妈
Look at you!
看看你啊
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine. I'm okay.
- 你还好吗
- 我还好 我没事儿
- Are you sure?
- I'm okay.
- 你确定吗
- 我没事儿
The kids were safe
to be kids again.
孩子们又能安全的当回孩子了
Widen your stance.
马步再宽点
Especially after their king, made
them all go to self-defense classes.
尤其是在他们的国王强制让他们去上了自卫课后
- Look at all those budding Space Vikings.
- And the most important part,
- 看这些崭露头角的太空维京啊
- 和最重要的部分,
The war cry!
战争咆哮
Even Heimdall's son,
甚至 海姆达尔的儿子
Axl Heimdallson,
Axl 海姆达尔
who could now do his
dad's freaky eye magic,
也可以使用他父亲的变态的全视之眼的魔法了
was becoming
quite the warrior.
正在成长为一个了不起的战士
The future of Asgard was secure.
阿斯加德的未来算是有保证了
Speaking of futures,
说到未来
I was forging one of my own.
我也在铸造我自己的
Now, that my body
has grown back.
现在我的身体也长回来了
With a dude I met called Dwayne.
和我遇到的一个叫(巨石)强森的伙伴一起
What about Thor, you ask?
你问索尔怎么样了
He embarked on a new journey.
他也开启了另一段旅程
Because he had found something to live for.
因为他已经找到了自己生命的意义
Something to love for.
和喜爱的事情
A little someone who
turned him from sad goat
一个小东西, 让他从一个悲伤之神
into dad goat.
变成爸爸之神
Breakfast is served, bon appetit.
早餐做好了, 来享用吧
Hello!
早上好
There you go!
来吃吧
Hey!
Breakfast!
嘿! 吃早餐了!
Excuse me.
打扰一下
What is that?
这是什么
They're...
They're panflaps from Earth.
它们是地球上的锅饼
I don't think
I like panflaps.
我不认为我喜欢锅饼
- You love them.
- No, I don't.
- 你会爱上的
- 不 我不喜欢
- Yes, you do.
- Never had that in my life.
- 你会的
- 我从来没吃过
Come on, eat up.
We have to go. We're gonna be late.
快吃吧, 赶紧
我们得赶紧出发了, 会迟到的
- Now, where are your boots?
- I'm wearing them.
- 你靴子在哪呢
- 我正穿着呢
You're not wearing those.
你不能穿那双
- Yes, I am.
- No, you're not.
- 我就穿
- 不 你不能穿
- Yes, I am.
- No, you're not.
- 我就穿
- 不 你不许穿
Go to hell, demon!
下地狱吧, 恶魔!
It's brand new.
Now, destroyed.
还是全新的,
现在 报废了
Thank you very much.
真是非常感谢
You know what,
you wear what you want.
好吧, 你想穿什么就穿什么吧
Don't come complaining to
me when your feet get sore.
一会儿脚酸的时候可别来跟我抱怨
Alright, you get no
sympathy here from me.
我可不再同情你了
Ugh, fine.
I'll wear the boots.
呃 好吧 我换靴子
Thank you.
谢谢
Now, remember what
my mother used to tell me.
记住我母亲曾经告诉我的
Listen to the grown ups.
听大人的话
And if you see anyone
scared or being picked on,
如果你看到任何人感到害怕或被欺负
- Look after them. Okay?
- Okay.
- 帮助他们,
- 好的
Most of all, have fun.
最重要的是, 过得开心
- Gotcha.
- 收到
Now, where is Mjölnir?
Where did I put it?
锤子哪去了
我把它放哪了
Over there,
sleeping in the bed.
在那呢
床上躺着呢
It's in the bed.
在床上?
Oh, wow!
That is not coming off.
还是擦不掉的
What did you do?
你做了什么?
Eh, she looked boring before.
它之前看起来太无聊了
Ah!
Supposed it did.
可能是有点
I love it.
我喜欢
Very creative.
很有创造力
Okay...
好的
Now, see the aliens down there?
The stripy ones?
现在, 看到下面带条纹的外星人了吗
They look nice.
他们看上去挺不错的
Yeah, they are nice.
是的, 他们人挺好的
That's why we have
to look after them.
所以我们得帮助他们
Got it.
明白
Protect the nice ones.
帮助好人
I love you, sweetie.
我爱你 , 甜心
Love you, Uncle Thor.
我也爱你, 索尔叔叔
They will always
be there for us.
他们会一直守护着我们
based on the eng subtitle of Hushrips/ProLover version
xiaoxu 译
It used to be that being a god,
meant something.
曾经作为神明, 是有意义的
People will whisper your name...
人们会轻声呼唤你的名字
Before sharing their
deepest hopes and dreams.
在分享他们心底的渴望和梦想之前
They begged you for mercy...
他们祈求你的宽恕
Without ever knowing,
if you're actually listening.
都不知道你究竟在没在听
Now...
现在
You know, they look to the sky.
知道吗, 他们望向天空
They don't ask us for lightning.
他们不再祈求闪电
They don't ask us for rain.
不再祈求降雨
They just want to see one
of their so-called superheroes.
他们只是想见到他们所谓的超级英雄们
When did we become the joke?
我们什么时候被沦为了笑柄
They will fear us again...
他们会再次对我们肃然起敬的
When Thor Odinson falls from the sky.
当索尔奥丁之子陨落的时候
Do you understand me, Hercules?
你听明白我的意思了吗 赫丘利斯?
- Do you understand, my son?
- Yes, father.
- 你明白了吗 我的孩子
- 明白了 父亲